 
 
1. Wonen  
 
Een huis regelen  
 
Sociale huur  û Social rent      
 
Woningbouwvereniging  û Housing association where you can register if 
you are looking for a rental home  
 
Woningcorporatie  û Housing association where you can register if you are 
looking for a rental home  
 
Wachtlijst  û Waiting list   
 
Urgentieverklaring  û Declaration of urgency  (in case you are waiting for a 
house in social rent)  
 
Vrije sector  û Rental houses that are not social rent  
 
Huisbaas  - Landlord  
 
Makelaar  - Realtor  
 
Huurcontract  û Rental contract  
 
Huurder  - Tenant  
 
Servicekosten  
 
Opzegtermijn  û Notice period  
 
Belastingdienst  û Tax authority  
 
Huurtoeslag  û Rent allowance; money people with low income can get 
back from the tax authority  
 
Hypotheek  - Mortgage  
 
Rente  
 
Belastingaangifte  û Tax return   
 
Hypotheekrenteaftrek û Interest deduction; deducting the interest  you pay 
on your mortgage from your income when doing your tax return  
 
 
 
Notaris  
 
Verzekeringen  û Insurances   
 
Aansprakelijkheidsverzekering  û Liability insurance  
 
Inboedelverzekering  û Home insurance  
 
 
Energie en communicatie  
 
Energiebedrijf  û Energy company  
 
Meterstand  û Meter reading (of gas, electricity, water)  
 
Energierekening  û Energy bill  
 
Termijnbedrag  û Monthly amount that needs to be paid for energy in your 
house  
 
Jaarrekening  û Annual bill  for energy in your house  
 
Duurzame energie  û Sustainable energy  
 
Nederlandse publieke omroep (NPO)  û Dutch public broadcaster  
 
Overheid  û Government  
 
Abonnement  û Subscription  
 
Storing  û Technical issue (mostly concerning  electricity)  
 
 
Onderhoud en woonomgeving  
 
Glasbak  û Glas s container  
 
Papierbak  û Paper container  
 
Groene container  û Container for vegetables, fruit and garden waste  
 
Groente, fruit, tuin  (GFT) container  - Container for vegetables, fruit and  
garden waste  
 
Plasticbak  û Plastic container  
 
 
 
Chemisch  afval û Chemical waste  
 
Klein chemisch afval  û Waste disposal  for all types of small chemical waste 
(batteries, paint etc.)  
 
Belasting  - Tax  
 
Ontheffing  û Exemption  
 
